[
    {
        "numb": 1,
        "question": "The complex organizational process through which computer-based information systems are developed and maintained best defines: ",
        "answer": "information systems analysis and design",
        "options": [
            "information systems analysis and design",
            "joint application design ",
            "prototyping ",
            "none of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 2,
        "question": "Software designed to support the payroll function would best be classified as: ",
        "answer": "application software ",
        "options": [
            "system software",
            "application software",
            "design software ",
            "analysis software"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 3,
        "question": "The person in an organization who has the primary responsibility for systems analysis and design is the: ",
        "answer": "systems analyst ",
        "options": [
            "end user",
            "internal auditor",
            "business manager",
            "systems analyst"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 4,
        "question": "Which of the following can be considered a goal of TPS development?",
        "answer": "all of the above ",
        "options": [
            " improve transaction processing by speeding it up",
            "use fewer people ",
            "improve efficiency and accuracy",
            "all of the above "
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 5,
        "question": "The phase of the SDLC in which an information system is systematically repaired and improved is referred to as: ",
        "answer": " maintenance",
        "options": [
            "analysis",
            "mplementation",
            " maintenance",
            "physical repair"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 6,
        "question": "Sources of software include:",
        "answer": "all of the above ",
        "options": [
            "mhardware manufacturersohammad",
            "packaged software providers",
            "application service providers",
            "all of the above "
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 7,
        "question": "The first administrative information system was: name is ",
        "answer": "General Electric’s payroll system",
        "options": [
            "General Motor’s order tracking system",
            "ord Motor Company’s order tracking system ",
            "General Electric’s payroll system",
            " Coca-Cola’s payroll system "
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 8,
        "question": " Coca-Cola’s payroll system  ",
        "answer": "all of the above.",
        "options": [
            "freeing up internal resources",
            "increasing processing efficiencies",
            "reducing time to market. ",
            "all of the above."
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 9,
        "question": "Hiring a company to run your applications at your site on your computers is an example of:  name is ",
        "answer": "outsourcing",
        "options": [
            "a turnkey system ",
            "outsourcing",
            "downsizing",
            "realignment"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 10,
        "question": "Which of the following is not a project planning activity? ",
        "answer": "establishing management procedures ",
        "options": [
            "setting a Baseline Project Plan",
            "identifying and assessing risk",
            "determining project standards and procedures",
            "establishing management procedures "
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 11,
        "question": "Which of the following is not a project close down phase?  ",
        "answer": "communicating the project status",
        "options": [
            "conducting post project reviews",
            "closing the customer contract ",
            "closing down the project",
            "communicating the project status"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 12,
        "question": "Any person, group of people, piece of equipment, or material used in accomplishing an activity is referred to as a(n): ",
        "answer": "resource",
        "options": [
            "resource",
            "entity",
            "identifier",
            "agent"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 13,
        "question": "The amount of time that an activity can be delayed without delaying the project refers to: ",
        "answer": "slack time ",
        "options": [
            "noncritical time",
            "slack time ",
            "down time ",
            "delay time "
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 14,
        "question": "Tangible benefits would include:",
        "answer": "motasem",
        "options": [
            "improved organizational planning",
            "ability to investigate more alternatives",
            "improved asset control utilization ",
            "lower transaction costs"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 15,
        "question": "Which of the following is a way projects can be identified? ",
        "answer": "motasem",
        "options": [
            "bottom-up source ",
            "upper-echelon source ",
            "top-down source ",
            "both a and c "
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 16,
        "question": "A statement that makes it clear what business a company is in is called a: ",
        "answer": "corporate policy statement ",
        "options": [
            "business statement ",
            "mission statement ",
            "goal statement",
            "corporate policy statement "
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 17,
        "question": "As a rule of thumb estimate, what percentage of the entire development effort should be devoted to the project initiation and planning process?  ",
        "answer": "between 10 and 20 percent",
        "options": [
            "between 10 and 20 percent",
            "less than 5 percent ",
            "less than 10 percent",
            "between 20 and 30 percent"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 18,
        "question": "Cost reduction and avoidance, error reduction, and increased flexibility are examples of:  ",
        "answer": "tangible benefits",
        "options": [
            "intangible benefits",
            "qualitative benefits ",
            "tangible benefits",
            "legal and contractual benefits "
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 19,
        "question": "The matrix that identifies the relationships between organizational entities and each business function is:  ",
        "answer": "unit-to-function",
        "options": [
            "location-to-unit ",
            "unit-to-function",
            "entity-to-process ",
            "function-to-process"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 20,
        "question": "An advantage of the bottom-up planning approach is:",
        "answer": "identifying pressing organizational problems ",
        "options": [
            "identifying pressing organizational problems ",
            "broader perspective ",
            "improved integration",
            "better understanding "
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 21,
        "question": "Which of the following is the first ISP step?",
        "answer": "Assess current IS-related assets",
        "options": [
            "Develop target blueprints",
            "Assess current IS-related assets",
            "Assess current IS-related assets",
            "Assign resources"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 22,
        "question": "Which of the following is a competitive strategy? ",
        "answer": "all of the above",
        "options": [
            "low-cost producer",
            "product differentiation",
            "product focus ",
            "all of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 23,
        "question": "Once a company has defined its mission and objectives:  ",
        "answer": "a competitive strategy can be formulated ",
        "options": [
            "goals can be established",
            "an information architecture can be developed",
            "project analysis can begin ",
            "a competitive strategy can be formulated "
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 24,
        "question": " A controlled process of initiating, planning, executing, and closing down a project best defines:  ",
        "answer": "project management ",
        "options": [
            "systems development ",
            "project management ",
            "project development",
            "systems management "
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 25,
        "question": "A planned undertaking of related activities to reach an objective that has a beginning and an end best defines:",
        "answer": "project",
        "options": [
            "task development",
            "activity plan ",
            "project ",
            "task schedule"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 26,
        "question": "Which of the following software evaluation criteria refers to the ease with which you or the vendor can customize the software?  ",
        "answer": "motasem",
        "options": [
            "cost",
            "vendor viability ",
            "functionality",
            "flexibility"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 27,
        "question": "When purchasing off-the-shelf software, you should consider:  ",
        "answer": "all of the above ",
        "options": [
            "all of the above ",
            "vendor viabilit",
            "vendor viabilit",
            "flexibility"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 28,
        "question": "Based on service revenue, which of the following companies is the top global software company? ",
        "answer": "EDS",
        "options": [
            "EDS",
            "Accenture",
            "Microsoft",
            "Compaq"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 29,
        "question": "myBased on 2002 total revenues, which of the following companies had the highest revenues?  name is ",
        "answer": "IBM",
        "options": [
            "Microsoft",
            "IBM",
            "Accenture",
            "NTT Data Corporation"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 30,
        "question": "my namWhich of the following are major categories of organizations that produce software? e is ",
        "answer": "all of the above",
        "options": [
            "hardware manufacturers",
            "custom software producers ",
            "all of the above ",
            "packaged software producers "
        ]
    }
]